When talking about proteins you usually think of food such as meat and egg-
-But rarely do we talk about the thousands of proteins that build our bodies.
Without them we would not exist.
There are several thousand protein in the body.
They are called the body's building blocks as they build up bones, tissues and muscles-
-But even hormones, enzymes and antibodies are proteins.
They are found everywhere in the body-
-And is of great importance for the body's functions and structure.
The proteins are produced in the body's cells, more specifically the ribosomes-
-cellen's small factories.
The protein gets specific properties-
-Dore depending on which amino acids are involved and their order.
The combinations are almost endless.
When the chain is done, it is folded together and the protein gets its unique structure.
In order for protein to be formed, the amino acids must be found in our bodies.
We cannot make all ourselves.
We get nine pieces through the food.
In the past, it was believed that proteins were unique to a specific tissue.
That they were just there.
But that theory is littered.
Today we know that a protein in the knee joint may be in your gut.
Proteins are not just building materials in tissues, muscles and bones.
They are much more than that and are behind many chemical processes.
Enzymes, receptors, hormones and antibodies are all protein-
-And has a role in our cell communication and interaction.
Hormones are formed in glands and transported to different organ-
-Where they affect different cells.
Receptors are protein that captures external signals-
-And sends them into the cell.
Antibodies Flag marks intruders in the body-
-and calls on the immune system's killer cells-